# Steven Dolbey

(321) 890-2488 • stevendolbey@gmail.com • stevendolbey.com

# **UX Designer**

Analytically-driven user experience designer with a degree in Web Design from the University of Central Florida. Skilled with Adobe Illustrator, HTML and CSS, and well-versed in wireframing and prototyping in Figma and Adobe XD. Experience working with nonprofits. Four years of experience designing for and managing live gaming events. Seeking an opportunity to improve digital products and experiences through user-centered design. Open to remote work and relocation within the United States. See my portfolio at <a href="stevendolbey.com">stevendolbey.com</a>

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Arts in Digital Media - Web Design**

University of Central Florida • Orlando, FL • GPA: 3.97 Major • Jun 2018 - Dec 2020

#### **PROJECTS**

# Florida Native Plant Society

Personal project • Jun 2021 - Mar 2023

- Redesigned the FNPS website with a focus on its extensive but intimidating native plant database.
- The goal was to get more native plants in the ground by making it easier for people to browse the database and find the right native plants for them.
- The web team at FNPS loved my project, so they invited me to work with them to bring it to life.
- The project involved auditing the website, sketching low-fidelity wireframes, conducting user research with the card sort method, defining a new visual style for their brand, and building high-fidelity Figma prototypes at desktop and mobile breakpoints.

#### Wheelies

User-Centered Design class at UCF • Jan 2020 - Apr 2020

- Applied user research, competitive analysis, and stakeholder surveys to design and build an interactive prototype
  of Wheelies, an app designed to help wheelchair users find accessible entrances, in Adobe XD (and later in
  Figma).
- Iterated on the prototype using feedback and insights from user testing with the think aloud protocol.

#### Planet 9

Web Design Workshop class at UCF • Jan 2020 - Apr 2020

- Designed Planet 9, our team's advocacy website for reinstating Pluto's planetary status, in Adobe XD.
- Saved the project from failure by redeveloping the website from scratch at the eleventh hour.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Florida Native Plant Society • Remote • Part-time • Jul 2023 - Present UX Designer

 Collaborated with directors and developers to find platforms and tools to help move the redesign forward at little to no cost to FNPS thanks to their nonprofit status.

- Developed growth-oriented strategies and designed presentations to build support for the redesign with stakeholders on the board.
- Facilitated communication between design, development, and stakeholders by introducing and setting up a Slack workspace for the team.
- Enabled improvements to location-based plant filters by merging updated ZIP code-based USDA hardiness zone data with the existing county-level data with a VLOOKUP in Microsoft Excel.

# Green Tea Tournaments • Melbourne, FL • Feb 2018 - Oct 2019

# Owner, Event Manager, Design Lead

- Organized, marketed, and executed successful monthly fighting game tournaments for upwards of 50 players across as many as 8 games.
- Managed and trained a diverse team of volunteers that helped with setup and cleanup, attendee check-in, concessions vending, graphic design, live-streaming, and bracket-running.
- Defined the brand for a new series of vaporwave-themed fighting game events by creating logos, graphics, and marketing materials in Adobe Illustrator, curating music, and selecting décor.

# Crown Productions Gaming • Melbourne, FL • Dec 2015 - Feb 2018 General Manager, Event Manager, Designer

- Grew fighting game tournament attendance from single digits to the highest on the Space Coast.
- Designed the UI for Brackette, an in-house front-end for Challonge.com that made it easier to run brackets with less staff by allowing players to self-report their scores, in Adobe XD.
- Improved satisfaction with lower-level players by implementing a variant of the innovative waterfall tournament format, which guaranteed them more competitive matches compared to traditional double-elimination brackets.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

**Adobe Certified Associate in Adobe Photoshop CS6** 

**Adobe Certified Associate in Adobe Illustrator CS6** 

# **SKILLS**

Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD, Affinity Designer, Card Sort Testing, Competitive Analysis, CSS, Data Analysis, Figma, GitHub, HTML, Information Architecture, Interaction Design, JavaScript, Mockups, PHP, Prototyping, Sketching, Typography, Usability Testing, User Research, Visual Studio Code, Web Accessibility